<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>workflow on Joseph V. Casillas</title>
    <link>/tags/workflow/</link>
    <description>Recent content in workflow on Joseph V. Casillas</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Joseph V. Casillas&lt;/br&gt;&amp;copy; 2019&lt;/br&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/workflow/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>R-Snippets</title>
      <link>/project/r_snippets/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/r_snippets/</guid>
      <description>This repository is a collection of snippets that I use in SublimeText for doing statistical analysis in R. The goal is straightforward: document the code that I use most often while doing linguistic research and make it readily available (and understandable) to other linguists. If you are interested in helping see the github repository. To install R-snippets see the package control page. To use a snippet, type the trigger and hit the tab key.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data pipelines in R</title>
      <link>/post/2015-05-18_data_pipelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2015 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2015-05-18_data_pipelines/</guid>
      <description>Overview So you thought up a clever experiment, got IRB approval, recruited participants and collected data… now what? New researchers are often confronted with an unfortunate surprise when it comes time to perform some kind of analysis on their data: they don’t know how, or even where to start. This can be a problem for something trivial, like obtaining simple descriptive statistics, or something much more complex, like fitting models, creating plots and making predictions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TikzDevice tutorial II: structuring a project</title>
      <link>/post/2013-05-17_tikz_-_projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2013 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2013-05-17_tikz_-_projects/</guid>
      <description>Overview This mini tutorial is part II about incorporating tikzDevice into your workflow. It explains the file structure necessary to successfully include tikzDevice plots into your LaTeX document. You must first have tikzDevice installed. If you don’t, see part I for more information.
 The structure A simple yet effective way to do reproducible research is to use R (for statistical analysis) directly in a LaTeX environment. There are two ways to accomplish this: (1) Sweave and (2) knitr.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>